

 $\searrow$ 

mailvaibhavchopra@gmail.co



+919319740960



Delhi, India



vaibhavchopra.ml



linkedin.com/in/vc2001



github.com/sudo-vaibhav



medium.com/@mailvaibhavch opra

# **SKILLS**

AWS

Blockchain

DevOns

Docker

O.U.

GranhOl

Kuhernetes

Linux

Microsoft Azure

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

Python

React

Tailwind

# **LANGUAGES**

### English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hind

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

# **INTERESTS**

Reading

**Fitness** 

Gaming

# Vaibhav Chopra

Software Engineer, Celo India Fellow, Student Researcher at Samsung Prism.

I'm a curious student of the art of Computer Science. I'm always ready to take up projects and determined to complete them successfully. I love to interact with people through webinars and mentoring in hackathons.

### **EDUCATION**

B.Tech. CSE

Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore

07/2019 - Present

Current CGPA - 9.39/10

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Software Developer**

Prisha Insurance Brokers Pvt. Ltd.

03/2021 - 04/2022

- Developed several applications responsible for vital operation from scratch.
- Spearheaded the use of cutting-edge technologies like GraphQL, Gatsby, MongoDB, React, and Progressive Web Apps to enhance developer and customer experience.
- Optimized the digital footprint and increased unique visitors by 50%.

# Blockchain India Fellow

Celo

06/2021 - 08/2021

- Developed several decentralized applications involving the using the WEB3 SDK.
- Contributed to open source and documenting core libraries using Storybook and Docusaurus.
- Conducted several presentations and talks on Celo.

### ORGANIZATIONS AND VOLUNTEERING

Community Lead at Student Technical Community (STC-VIT) (03/2021 - 03/2022)

Streamlined processes leading to a 40% increase in technical project output and social media stats.

# **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

### Solidity Push Notification Service - Push Notifications for Web3

Improved the User Experience of Ethereum-based blockchain applications. Analyzed the technical limitations and developed a thoroughly tested solution. Employed modern technologies like Solidity, Jest, Docusaurus, Kubernetes and Web Sockets. sudo-vaibhav/solidity-push-notification-service (github.com).

### Smriti - Alzheimer's Patient Assistant App

Engineered a custom-made pair of glasses fitted with a camera module using Raspberry Pi for face detection along with a companion application built with Webpack and Typescript. Conducted a case study and devised an innovative solution to a widespread problem. <a href="mailto:sudo-vaibhav/smriti-app">sudo-vaibhav/smriti-app</a> (github.com)

### DCompute - A Decentralized WASM Powered Compute Marketplace

 A project that tackles the semiconductor shortage and increasing cloud computing bills by allowing users to exchange their time and compute resources, through a platform powered by Web Assembly, AssemblyScript, React and Node JS. sudo-vaibhav/DCompute (github.com)

### **ACHIEVEMENTS**

DevSoc-2021 by CodeChef - Best UI/UX and Rarible NFT Track Winner (05/2021)

A 36-hour international hackathon conducted by CodeChef VIT.

Hackout by Headout Winner - 3rd position worldwide (11/2020)

A 48-hour international virtual hackathon with over 750+ participants all across the globe.